{
  "category": "religion",
  "questions":[
    {
      "question": "The god Quetzalcoatl is recognized in",
      "answer":   "D: Aztec religion",
      "optionA":  "A: Cherokee religion",
      "optionB":  "B: All Native American religions",
      "optionC":  "C: Modoc religion",
      "optionD":  "D: Aztec religion"
    },
    {
      "question": "The ancestral spirits of the Pueblo peoples are known as",
      "answer":   "B: Kachinas",
      "optionA":  "A: The Hero Twins",
      "optionB":  "B: Kachinas",
      "optionC":  "C: Jump Dancers",
      "optionD":  "D: None of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "The cycle of birth, death and rebirth. You pay for good or bad deeds based on your behavior.",
      "answer":   "B: reincarnation",
      "optionA":  "A: karma",
      "optionB":  "B: reincarnation",
      "optionC":  "C: Hinduism",
      "optionD":  "D: caste system"
    },
    {
      "question": "Weekly day of rest and prayer. This is on Saturday for the Jews.",
      "answer":   "A: Sabbath",
      "optionA":  "A: Sabbath",
      "optionB":  "B: Abraham",
      "optionC":  "C: Moses",
      "optionD":  "D: Diaspora"
    },
    {
      "question": "The principles (Buddhism) that rule life and promise an end to suffering.",
      "answer":   "A: 4 Noble Truths",
      "optionA":  "A: 4 Noble Truths",
      "optionB":  "B: 10 Commandments",
      "optionC":  "C: 5 Pillars",
      "optionD":  "D: Holy Grail"
    },
    {
      "question": "A special leader sent by God in order to guide people and set up God's rule.",
      "answer":   "A: Messiah",
      "optionA":  "A: Messiah",
      "optionB":  "B: disciple",
      "optionC":  "C: apostle",
      "optionD":  "D: parable"
    },
    {
      "question": "The two civilizations of India where Hinduism originated",
      "answer":   "C: Aryans & Harappans",
      "optionA":  "A: Mecca",
      "optionB":  "B: Jerusalem",
      "optionC":  "C: Aryans & Harappans",
      "optionD":  "D: Rome"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Hinduism and Buddhism, the end result of all of a person's good and bad acts, which determines his or her rebirth.",
      "answer":   "B: karma",
      "optionA":  "A: reincarnation",
      "optionB":  "B: karma",
      "optionC":  "C: caste system",
      "optionD":  "D: parable"
    },
    {
      "question": "The sacred text of the religion of Islam.",
      "answer":   "C: Qu'ran",
      "optionA":  "A: Torah?",
      "optionB":  "B: Bible",
      "optionC":  "C: Qu'ran",
      "optionD":  "D: Vedas"
    },
    {
      "question": "A journey to a place considered sacred for religious purposes.",
      "answer":   "A: pilgrimage",
      "optionA":  "A: pilgrimage",
      "optionB":  "B: parable",
      "optionC":  "C: hike",
      "optionD":  "D: Penance"
    },

    {
      "question": "What holiday ends Ramadan?",
      "answer":   "C: Eid al-Fitr",
      "optionA":  "A: Ashura",
      "optionB":  "B: New Year",
      "optionC":  "C: Eid al-Fitr",
      "optionD":  "D: Rama Navami"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Korean festival of the winter solstice?",
      "answer":   "D: Dongji",
      "optionA":  "A: Tet",
      "optionB":  "B: New Year’s Eve",
      "optionC":  "C: Yom Kippur",
      "optionD":  "D: Dongji"
    },
    {
      "question": "To whom is the Cambodian temple Angkor Wat dedicated?",
      "answer":   "C: Vishnu",
      "optionA":  "A: Moses",
      "optionB":  "B: Buddha",
      "optionC":  "C: Vishnu",
      "optionD":  "D: Krishna"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is honored with the holiday Ganesha Chaturthi?",
      "answer":   "C: Ganesha",
      "optionA":  "A: Ganymede",
      "optionB":  "B: Goliath",
      "optionC":  "C: Ganesha",
      "optionD":  "D: Gilgamesh"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the largest religious structure in the world?",
      "answer":   "B: Angkor Wat",
      "optionA":  "A: the Kremlin",
      "optionB":  "B: Angkor Wat",
      "optionC":  "C: Notre Dame Cathedral",
      "optionD":  "D: the Temple of Heaven"
    },
    {
      "question": "What religion do more than two-thirds of the people of India practice?",
      "answer":   "A: Hinduism",
      "optionA":  "A: Hinduism",
      "optionB":  "B: Buddhism",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Sufism"
    },
    {
      "question": "What religion practices nonviolence?",
      "answer":   "A: Jainism",
      "optionA":  "A: Jainism",
      "optionB":  "B: Jaundism",
      "optionC":  "C: animism",
      "optionD":  "D: shamanism"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which part of the world did Buddhism first come into being?",
      "answer":   "B: North East India",
      "optionA":  "A: Japan",
      "optionB":  "B: North East India",
      "optionC":  "C: South America",
      "optionD":  "D: West Africa"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the religion of Jewish people?",
      "answer":   "C: Judaism",
      "optionA":  "A: Bar Mitzvah",
      "optionB":  "B: Hebrewism",
      "optionC":  "C: Judaism",
      "optionD":  "D: Yiddishism"
    },
    {
      "question": "The sacred scriptures of Hinduism are collectively known as what?",
      "answer":   "C: The Veda",
      "optionA":  "A: The Scrolls",
      "optionB":  "B: The Siva",
      "optionC":  "C: The Veda",
      "optionD":  "D: The Vishnu"
    },

    {
      "question": "Shinto is the indigenous religious belief and practice of which country ?",
      "answer":   "B: Japan",
      "optionA":  "A: Bhutan",
      "optionB":  "B: Japan",
      "optionC":  "C: Malaysia",
      "optionD":  "D: Pakistan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Sunnites and Shi'ites are followers of which religion?",
      "answer":   "A: Islam",
      "optionA":  "A: Islam",
      "optionB":  "B: Judaism",
      "optionC":  "C: Shintoism",
      "optionD":  "D: Sikhism"
    },
    {
      "question": "Devotees of which pre-Islamic religion from Iran are called Parsees?",
      "answer":   "D: Zoroastrianism",
      "optionA":  "A: Confucianism",
      "optionB":  "B: Shintoism",
      "optionC":  "C: Taoism",
      "optionD":  "D: Zoroastrianism"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which century did Sikhism originate?",
      "answer":   "A: 15th",
      "optionA":  "A: 15th",
      "optionB":  "B: 16th",
      "optionC":  "C: 17th",
      "optionD":  "D: 18th"
    },
    {
      "question": "When translated from Hebrew, what does the term 'rabbi' mean ?",
      "answer":   "D: My teacher",
      "optionA":  "A: My father",
      "optionB":  "B: My guide",
      "optionC":  "C: My inspiration",
      "optionD":  "D: My teacher"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the Hindu system of hierarchy based upon relative purity?",
      "answer":   "A: Caste",
      "optionA":  "A: Caste",
      "optionB":  "B: Class",
      "optionC":  "C: Demographic",
      "optionD":  "D: Segmented"
    },
    {
      "question": "What name is given to the Buddhist practice of mental concentration?",
      "answer":   "B: Meditation",
      "optionA":  "A: Mediation",
      "optionB":  "B: Meditation",
      "optionC":  "C: Moderation",
      "optionD":  "D: Modification"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many 'Pillars Of Islam' are Muslims asked to practice?",
      "answer":   "C: 5",
      "optionA":  "A: 3",
      "optionB":  "B: 4",
      "optionC":  "C: 5",
      "optionD":  "D: 6"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is the lunar-based Hindu calendar adjusted to the solar calendar?",
      "answer":   "C: An extra month, every 30 months",
      "optionA":  "A: An extra day, every third week",
      "optionB":  "B: An extra minute, every 14 hours",
      "optionC":  "C: An extra month, every 30 months",
      "optionD":  "D: An extra week, every quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was said to be the essence of Buddha's early preaching?",
      "answer":   "B: 4 Noble Truths",
      "optionA":  "A: 4 Ethical Truths",
      "optionB":  "B: 4 Noble Truths",
      "optionC":  "C: 4 Fundamental Truths",
      "optionD":  "D: 4 Undisputed Truths"
    },

    {
      "question": "What does the Sikh surname 'Singh' mean?",
      "answer":   "A: Lion",
      "optionA":  "A: Lion",
      "optionB":  "B: Master",
      "optionC":  "C: Traveller",
      "optionD":  "D: Worker"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many males constitute a quorum at a Jewish public religious ceremony?",
      "answer":   "D: 10",
      "optionA":  "A: 4",
      "optionB":  "B: 6",
      "optionC":  "C: 8",
      "optionD":  "D: 10"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was regarded as the 'Second Sage' of the Confucian heritage?",
      "answer":   "C: Mencius",
      "optionA":  "A: Chu Hsi",
      "optionB":  "B: Hsun--tzu",
      "optionC":  "C: Mencius",
      "optionD":  "D: Tung Chung-shu"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which word means \"mystical\", \"superior\" or \"divine\" in the Shinto faith?",
      "answer":   "A: Kami",
      "optionA":  "A: Kami",
      "optionB":  "B: Shojiki",
      "optionC":  "C: Tenri",
      "optionD":  "D: Ujigami"
    },
    {
      "question": "For how long has Taoism shaped Chinese life?",
      "answer":   "D: Over 2000 years",
      "optionA":  "A: Over 500 years",
      "optionB":  "B: Over 1000 years",
      "optionC":  "C: Over 1500 years",
      "optionD":  "D: Over 2000 years"
    },
    {
      "question": "Approximately how many Zoroastrians are there in the world?",
      "answer":   "B: 2.6 million",
      "optionA":  "A: 1.6 million",
      "optionB":  "B: 2.6 million",
      "optionC":  "C: 16 million",
      "optionD":  "D: 26 million"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to the Qur'an, what is regarded as the cardinal sin of man?",
      "answer":   "D: Pride",
      "optionA":  "A: Adultery",
      "optionB":  "B: Dishonesty",
      "optionC":  "C: Greed",
      "optionD":  "D: Pride"
    },
    {
      "question": "Christianity can be divided into three principle groups; Roman Catholic and which two others?",
      "answer":   "D: Eastern Orthodox and Protestant",
      "optionA":  "A: Anglican and Non-Conformist",
      "optionB":  "B: Baptist and Methodist",
      "optionC":  "C: Calvinist and Lutheran",
      "optionD":  "D: Eastern Orthodox and Protestant"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first great missionary of Christianity?",
      "answer":   "C: St Paul",
      "optionA":  "A: St Francis",
      "optionB":  "B: St Nicholas",
      "optionC":  "C: St Paul",
      "optionD":  "D: St Sebastian"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Christian movement was founded by John Wesley?",
      "answer":   "C: Methodism",
      "optionA":  "A: Calvinism",
      "optionB":  "B: Lutheranism",
      "optionC":  "C: Methodism",
      "optionD":  "D: Mormonism"
    },

    {
      "question": "What are the primary sources of information about Jesus Christ?",
      "answer":   "B: The Gospels",
      "optionA":  "A: The Book of Psalms",
      "optionB":  "B: The Gospels",
      "optionC":  "C: The Old Testament",
      "optionD":  "D: The Pentateuch"
    },
    {
      "question": "What name is given to the tomb where Jesus Christ was allegedly buried?",
      "answer":   "B: Holy Sepulchre",
      "optionA":  "A: Holy Grave",
      "optionB":  "B: Holy Sepulchre",
      "optionC":  "C: Holy Shrine",
      "optionD":  "D: Holy Tomb"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do Christians recognise as the Trinity?",
      "answer":   "B: Father, Son and Holy Spirit",
      "optionA":  "A: Bethlehem, Nazareth and Jerusalem",
      "optionB":  "B: Father, Son and Holy Spirit",
      "optionC":  "C: Gold, Frankincense and Myrrh",
      "optionD":  "D: Jesus, Mary and Joseph"
    },
    {
      "question": "Within which movement did Christianity begin?",
      "answer":   "D: Judaism",
      "optionA":  "A: Animism",
      "optionB":  "B: Buddhism",
      "optionC":  "C: Hinduism",
      "optionD":  "D: Judaism"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do Jehovah's Witnesses call their place of worship?",
      "answer":   "A: Kingdom Hall",
      "optionA":  "A: Kingdom Hall",
      "optionB":  "B: Redemption Hall",
      "optionC":  "C: Resolution Hall",
      "optionD":  "D: Salvation Hall"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the Christian calendar what is represented by Ash Wednesday?",
      "answer":   "D: The first day of Lent",
      "optionA":  "A: The beginning of Spring",
      "optionB":  "B: The end of Winter",
      "optionC":  "C: The first day of Advent",
      "optionD":  "D: The first day of Lent"
    },
    {
      "question": "What differentiates \"Eucharist\", \"Lord's Supper\" and \"Holy Communion\"?",
      "answer":   "A: Nothing - all the same sacrament",
      "optionA":  "A: Nothing - all the same sacrament",
      "optionB":  "B: Given at different times of day",
      "optionC":  "C: Given by different levels of priest",
      "optionD":  "D: Given at different times of year"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was elected head of the Roman Catholic church in April 2005?",
      "answer":   "D: Pope Benedict XVI",
      "optionA":  "A: Pope Benedict X",
      "optionB":  "B: Pope Benedict XII",
      "optionC":  "C: Pope Benedict XIV",
      "optionD":  "D: Pope Benedict XVI"
    },
    {
      "question": "When was Christian reformer Martin Luther excommunicated?",
      "answer":   "B: 1521",
      "optionA":  "A: 1501",
      "optionB":  "B: 1521",
      "optionC":  "C: 1541",
      "optionD":  "D: 1561"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which year did Robert Runcie, former Archbishop of Canterbury, die?",
      "answer":   "A: 2000",
      "optionA":  "A: 2000",
      "optionB":  "B: 2001",
      "optionC":  "C: 2002",
      "optionD":  "D: 2003"
    },

    {
      "question": "What leader of Buddhist Tibet was exiled after the communist Chinese invaded and conquered Tibet during the 1950s?",
      "answer":   "A: Dalai Lama",
      "optionA":  "A: Dalai Lama",
      "optionB":  "B: Karmapa Lama",
      "optionC":  "C: Panchen Lama",
      "optionD":  "D: Reg Llama (of Brixton)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Buddhism is an offshoot of what other major world religion?",
      "answer":   "D: Hinduism",
      "optionA":  "A: Christianity",
      "optionB":  "B: Zoroastrianism",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Hinduism"
    },
    {
      "question": "Buddhism is the religion of a substantial portion of the population of which of the following countries?",
      "answer":   "A: Bhutan",
      "optionA":  "A: Bhutan",
      "optionB":  "B: Guinea-Bissau",
      "optionC":  "C: Poland",
      "optionD":  "D: Uruguay"
    },
    {
      "question": "When a Buddhist individual reaches enlightenment, it is said that they reach a certain state that can be literally translated as 'snuffing out'. What is this state?",
      "answer":   "D: Nirvana",
      "optionA":  "A: Confusion",
      "optionB":  "B: Cogito, ergo sum",
      "optionC":  "C: Texas",
      "optionD":  "D: Nirvana"
    },
    {
      "question": "A Sanskrit word meaning 'action' or 'fate', a lot of people equate it to 'what comes around goes around'. What is this term?",
      "answer":   "B: Karma",
      "optionA":  "A: Bodhi",
      "optionB":  "B: Karma",
      "optionC":  "C: Sutra",
      "optionD":  "D: Sangha"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Buddhists believe in following a path to enlightenment. How many fold is this path?",
      "answer":   "C: 8",
      "optionA":  "A: 60",
      "optionB":  "B: 1,000",
      "optionC":  "C: 8",
      "optionD":  "D: 100"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a popular form of Buddhism in Japan?",
      "answer":   "C: Zen",
      "optionA":  "A: Totoro",
      "optionB":  "B: Pikachu",
      "optionC":  "C: Zen",
      "optionD":  "D: Matsushita"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the real name of the founder of Buddhism?",
      "answer":   "C: Siddharta Gautama",
      "optionA":  "A: Borobodur",
      "optionB":  "B: Ashoka",
      "optionC":  "C: Siddharta Gautama",
      "optionD":  "D: Suryabaya"
    },
    {
      "question": "The largest Buddhist Monastery in India is located at ______?",
      "answer":   "C: Tawang, Arunachal Pradesh",
      "optionA":  "A: Gangktok, Sikkim",
      "optionB":  "B: Dharamshala, Himachal Pradesh",
      "optionC":  "C: Tawang, Arunachal Pradesh",
      "optionD":  "D: Sarnath, Uttar Pradesh"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Guru/s Contributed to Sri Guru Granth Sahib Ji ?",
      "answer":   "B: First Five and Ninth Guru",
      "optionA":  "A: Fifth Guru ",
      "optionB":  "B: First Five and Ninth Guru",
      "optionC":  "C: First Five and Tenth Guru",
      "optionD":  "D: All Gurus"
    },

    {
      "question": "A follower of Islam is called a _____________________.",
      "answer":   "C: Muslim",
      "optionA":  "A: Brahman",
      "optionB":  "B: Missionary",
      "optionC":  "C: Muslim",
      "optionD":  "D: Hindi"
    },
    {
      "question": "The founder of Islam is  ___________________.",
      "answer":   "D: Muhammad",
      "optionA":  "A: Siddhartha Gautama",
      "optionB":  "B: Abraham",
      "optionC":  "C: Jesus",
      "optionD":  "D: Muhammad"
    },
    {
      "question": "The belief in one god is called ________________",
      "answer":   "A: Monotheism",
      "optionA":  "A: Monotheism",
      "optionB":  "B: Polytheism",
      "optionC":  "C: Religion",
      "optionD":  "D: Meditation"
    },
    {
      "question": "The sacred text (holy book) of the Christians is the _______________.",
      "answer":   "B: Bible",
      "optionA":  "A: Qu'ran or Koran",
      "optionB":  "B: Bible",
      "optionC":  "C: The Vedas",
      "optionD":  "D: The Torah"
    },
    {
      "question": "The founder of Buddhism is ______________________",
      "answer":   "A: Siddhartha Gautama",
      "optionA":  "A: Siddhartha Gautama",
      "optionB":  "B: Jesus",
      "optionC":  "C: Muhammad",
      "optionD":  "D: Abraham"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some of the sacred texts of the Hindus include __________________",
      "answer":   "C: The Vedas, Maharbharata, and the Upanishads",
      "optionA":  "A: The Torah and the Hebrew Bible",
      "optionB":  "B: The Qu'ran and the teachings Abraham",
      "optionC":  "C: The Vedas, Maharbharata, and the Upanishads",
      "optionD":  "D: The ancient canticle"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man was the founder of Judaism",
      "answer":   "B: Abraham",
      "optionA":  "A: Solomon",
      "optionB":  "B: Abraham",
      "optionC":  "C: Jesus",
      "optionD":  "D: Mohammad"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is NOT one of the Five Pillars of Faith associated with Islam?",
      "answer":   "D: Become a missionary in a foreign land",
      "optionA":  "A: Give to charity",
      "optionB":  "B: Pray 5 x's per day",
      "optionC":  "C: Travel to Mecca at least once in your lifetime",
      "optionD":  "D: Become a missionary in a foreign land"
    },
    {
      "question": "All three major monotheistic religions developed in this region.",
      "answer":   "A: Europe",
      "optionA":  "A: Europe",
      "optionB":  "B: North America",
      "optionC":  "C: Middle East or Southwest Asia",
      "optionD":  "D: China"
    },
    {
      "question": "Hinduism and Buddhism both developed in this area.",
      "answer":   "C: India",
      "optionA":  "A: Middle East",
      "optionB":  "B: Europe",
      "optionC":  "C: India",
      "optionD":  "D: Italy"
    },

    {
      "question": "Judaism, Christianity, and Islam all ____________________________.",
      "answer":   "C: Worship only one God",
      "optionA":  "A: Believe in many divine Gods",
      "optionB":  "B: Worship only one God",
      "optionC":  "C: Follow the teachings of the Qu'ran",
      "optionD":  "D: Believe Jesus was the son of God"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Torah is the sacred writing (holy book) for which religion?",
      "answer":   "A: Judaism",
      "optionA":  "A: Judaism",
      "optionB":  "B: Christianity",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: None"
    },
    {
      "question": "The belief that the soul never dies but is continually reborn or reincarnated is associated with which religion?",
      "answer":   "D: Hinduism and Buddhism",
      "optionA":  "A: Islam",
      "optionB":  "B: Christianity",
      "optionC":  "C: Judaism",
      "optionD":  "D: Hinduism and Buddhism"
    },
    {
      "question": "Following the Eightfold Path and the Four Noble Truths to achieve enlightenment is associated with which religion?",
      "answer":   "A: Buddhism",
      "optionA":  "A: Buddhism",
      "optionB":  "B: Hinduism",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Christianity"
    },
    {
      "question": "This religion can be divided into Catholic, Protestant, and Orthodox sects.",
      "answer":   "B: Christianity",
      "optionA":  "A: Judaism",
      "optionB":  "B: Christianity",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Buddhism"
    },
    {
      "question": "Diwali, the festival of Lights is important to which religion?",
      "answer":   "D: Hinduism",
      "optionA":  "A: Judaism",
      "optionB":  "B: Christianity",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Hinduism"
    },
    {
      "question": "Ramadan is the holy month of fasting for which religion?",
      "answer":   "C: Islam",
      "optionA":  "A: Judaism",
      "optionB":  "B: Christianity",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Hinduism"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do Sikhs treat their women?",
      "answer":   "A: With respect, dignity and equality",
      "optionA":  "A: With respect, dignity and equality",
      "optionB":  "B: Like inferiors",
      "optionC":  "C: Harshly, beating and verbally abusing them",
      "optionD":  "D: They make them wear veils and be secluded"
    },
    {
      "question": "The clergy for Christianity are called _______________.",
      "answer":   "B: Priests or ministers",
      "optionA":  "A: Rabbis",
      "optionB":  "B: Priests or ministers",
      "optionC":  "C: Imams",
      "optionD":  "D: Brahman"
    },
    {
      "question": "The clergy for Judaism are called _________________.",
      "answer":   "C: Rabbis",
      "optionA":  "A: Monks",
      "optionB":  "B: Priests",
      "optionC":  "C: Rabbis",
      "optionD":  "D: Imams"
    },

    {
      "question": "What are the clergy in Buddhism called?",
      "answer":   "C: Monks",
      "optionA":  "A: Savior.",
      "optionB":  "B: Priests",
      "optionC":  "C: Monks",
      "optionD":  "D: Rabbis"
    },
    {
      "question": "Gurus are a type of clergy in what religion?",
      "answer":   "D: Hinduism",
      "optionA":  "A: Judaism",
      "optionB":  "B: Christianity",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Hinduism"
    },
    {
      "question": "There are no official clergy in Islam, but people who lead prayers at a mosque are called _________.",
      "answer":   "A: Imams",
      "optionA":  "A: Imams",
      "optionB":  "B: Rabbis",
      "optionC":  "C: Priests",
      "optionD":  "D: Monks"
    },
    {
      "question": "This religion is the oldest religion of the five major world religions.",
      "answer":   "A: Hinduism",
      "optionA":  "A: Hinduism",
      "optionB":  "B: Buddhism",
      "optionC":  "C: Judaism",
      "optionD":  "D: Islam"
    },
    {
      "question": "Check the two main sects of Islam.",
      "answer":   "C: Sunni and Shia",
      "optionA":  "A: Tibetan and Reformed",
      "optionB":  "B: Tibetan and Sunni",
      "optionC":  "C: Sunni and Shia",
      "optionD":  "D: Shia and Tibetan"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the language of Judaism?",
      "answer":   "C: Hebrew",
      "optionA":  "A: Greek",
      "optionB":  "B: Arabic",
      "optionC":  "C: Hebrew",
      "optionD":  "D: Polish"
    },
    {
      "question": "Jews who keep kosher",
      "answer":   "B: Follow a dietary law of eating",
      "optionA":  "A: Must pray five times a day",
      "optionB":  "B: Follow a dietary law of eating",
      "optionC":  "C: Face Israel when they pray",
      "optionD":  "D: Must visit the Western Wailing Wall"
    },
    {
      "question": "The pope is the leader of the _____ church in Christianity.",
      "answer":   "A: Roman Catholic",
      "optionA":  "A: Roman Catholic",
      "optionB":  "B: Greek Orthodox",
      "optionC":  "C: Baptist",
      "optionD":  "D: Methodist"
    },
    {
      "question": "Bhishma chose a particular time for his death. What was this time called?",
      "answer":   "D: Uttarayan",
      "optionA":  "A: Bhramakaal",
      "optionB":  "B: Sainkaal",
      "optionC":  "C: Suprabhaat",
      "optionD":  "D: Uttarayan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which aspect of African traditional religions has to do with rituals for events like marriage, birth, and death?",
      "answer":   "B: Rites of passage",
      "optionA":  "A: Supreme god",
      "optionB":  "B: Rites of passage",
      "optionC":  "C: Ancestral spirits",
      "optionD":  "D: Nature spirits"
    },

    {
      "question": "Which aspect of African traditional religions has to do with relatives who have died?",
      "answer":   "B: Ancestral spirits",
      "optionA":  "A: Supreme god.",
      "optionB":  "B: Ancestral spirits",
      "optionC":  "C: Rites of passage",
      "optionD":  "D: Nature spirits"
    },
    {
      "question": "The sacred scriptures of Hinduism are collectively known as what?",
      "answer":   "C: The Veda",
      "optionA":  "A: The Scrolls",
      "optionB":  "B: The Siva",
      "optionC":  "C: The Veda",
      "optionD":  "D: The Vishnu"
    },
    {
      "question": "The oldest Monotheistic Religion in the world is",
      "answer":   "A: Judaism",
      "optionA":  "A: Judaism",
      "optionB":  "B: Christianity",
      "optionC":  "C: Islam",
      "optionD":  "D: Zoroastrianism"
    },
    {
      "question": "What remains do Jews visit and travel to in order to worship?",
      "answer":   "A: Hinduism",
      "optionA":  "A: The Western Wall",
      "optionB":  "B: The Kaaba",
      "optionC":  "C: The Torah",
      "optionD":  "D: The Parthenon"
    },
    {
      "question": "”Donyi Polo” is a religion / tradition followed by some tribals of which among the following states?",
      "answer":   "B: Arunachal Pradesh",
      "optionA":  "A: Meghalaya",
      "optionB":  "B: Arunachal Pradesh",
      "optionC":  "C: Nagaland",
      "optionD":  "D: Sikkim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the 'ethical religions'?",
      "answer":   "C: Hinduism",
      "optionA":  "A: Buddhism",
      "optionB":  "B: Confucianism",
      "optionC":  "C: Hinduism",
      "optionD":  "D: Taoism"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Durkheim, religion separates objects and symbols into the sacred and which of the following?",
      "answer":   "D: the profane",
      "optionA":  "A: the profound",
      "optionB":  "B: the profuse",
      "optionC":  "C: the profitable",
      "optionD":  "D: the profane"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which of these countries is Orthodox Christianity the dominant religion?",
      "answer":   "B: Greece",
      "optionA":  "A: Finland",
      "optionB":  "B: Greece",
      "optionC":  "C: Ireland",
      "optionD":  "D: Spain"
    },
    {
      "question": "Of which of the following, according to Marx, does religion provide an example?",
      "answer":   "A: alienation",
      "optionA":  "A: alienation",
      "optionB":  "B: anomie",
      "optionC":  "C: authority",
      "optionD":  "D: animism"
    },
    {
      "question": "'New age' movements are an example of which type of religious movement?",
      "answer":   "A: world-affirming",
      "optionA":  "A: world-affirming",
      "optionB":  "B: world-rejecting",
      "optionC":  "C: world-enhancing",
      "optionD":  "D: world-accommodating"
    }

  ]
}